# Enkhmanlai "Manlai" Amarsaikhan

Data Scientist | San Francisco Bay Area | <u>a.enkhmanlai@gmail.com</u> (617) 893 - 3507 | <a href="https://amanlai.github.io/">https://amanlai.github.io/</a> |

## **Summary**

An economist / analyst with 5+ years of experience in cleaning, manipulating and exploring data, and using data mining models to deliver insights and implement solutions to social and economic problems. Have an advanced understanding of statistical, mathematical and other analytical methods and is an effective Python programmer, with a Master's degree in Economics.

#### **Skills**

- Languages: Python (scikit-learn, pandas, numpy, statsmodels), SQL, Git Bash, LaTeX, Matlab
- Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau
- Database Management: SQLite, BigQuery
- Supervised / Unsupervised Machine Learning: Regularization with Lasso, Ridge, kNN, Random Forest, Linear/Logistic Regression, Bagging/Boosting Models, Model Evaluation, Cross-Validation, Grid-Search
- Neural Networks: Regularizing Dense and/or Convolutional NN, LSTM
- Natural Language Processing: Tf-idf, NLTK
- Economics: Statistical Analysis, Experiment Design, Applied Econometrics, Research Methodology, Causal Inference, ARIMA, VAR Models

# **Experience**

General Assembly

Sep - Dec 2022

Remote

Data Science Immersive Student

- Collision Prediction in NYC
  - Built a classification model using the scikit-learn library in Python that classifies the severity of vehicle collisions in NYC that correctly classifies the positive class 30 percentage points better than the baseline.
  - Built an autoregressive LSTM neural network using the Keras library in Python that correctly forecasts the weekly collision total with an R<sup>2</sup>-score of 0.99.
- Subreddit Classification
  - Built a Python module that scrapes Reddit data, extracts features using NLP and employs grid-search to tune hyperparameters of ML models such as logistic regression, SVM, random forest and bagging/boosting models
  - Employed the module to build a classification model that accurately classifies subreddits
    35 percentage points better than the baseline
- Housing Price Prediction
  - Using the pandas library in Python, cleaned and explored a housing market dataset, feature-engineered and designed a linear regression model using the scikit-learn library that predicts 92% of the variation in housing prices

# Oyuny Tsomorlig Impex LLC

Sep 2017 - Aug 2022

Data Analyst / Economist

Remote

- Applied statistical, mathematical and other analytical methods to analyze and interpret key points from gathered data
- Led a team of economists in designing and conducting surveys and field experiments to collect data, cleaning and wrangling data, and building and analyzing data mining models
- Developed monthly roadmaps based on impact, effort and results, worked with stakeholders to achieve short-term and long-term goals on projects
- Collaborated with researchers by implementing machine learning models to analyze image data whose results were presented at an international conference

**Boston College** 

Sep 2015 - Aug 2020

Graduate Student Researcher

Chestnut Hill, MA

- Conducted own research in the field of microeconomics and matching market theory, produced 2 academic research papers and presented results to research workshops
- Wrote scalable and effective code in Python and Matlab for matching theory algorithms, linear and nonlinear optimization problems that were used to analyze and interpret data in research
- Designed, prepared and taught 3 elective-level college courses as the sole instructor for 3 years
- Helped students better understand course material by working through problems and relating course material to real-world situations

#### Awards

| Japanese Government (MEXT) Scholarship (Full Tuition Remission and Stipend) | 2007 - 2012 |
|---|-------------|
| Best Paper Award, "Geoinformation-2012" International Conference            | 2012        |
| Full Tuition Remission and Stipend, Boston College                          | 2013 - 2018 |

### **Education**

| General Assembly               | Sep - Dec 2022 |
|--------------------------------|----------------|
| Data Science Immersive Student | Remote         |

| Boston College        | Sep 2015 - Aug 2020 |
|-----------------------|---------------------|
| Non-degree coursework | Chestnut Hill, MA   |

Passed doctoral comprehensive examinations in top-5% of class

| Boston College  | Sep 2013 - May 2015 |
|-----------------|---------------------|
| MA in Economics | Chestnut Hill, MA   |

| University of Tokyo | Apr 2008 - Mar 2012 |
|---------------------|---------------------|
| BA in Economics     | Tokyo, Japan        |

Placed 1st overall on entrance examinations for MEXT scholarship students